ラジオ英会話 ハートでつかめ 英語の極意 講師の大西 博人です
さあ 金曜復習会 今日も頑張っていきましょう
さあ それでは早速始めていきましょう
今週のリビュー 金曜日は復習会です
最初のコーナーはこちら
Listening Challenge
OK, let's review this week's dialogues
Listen to the questions and pick which one of the three options is the correct answer
Let's start with Monday's dialogue
Here's the question
Who wrote the letter?
A. Brendan
B. A samurai who taught English
A. A samurai who taught English
or C. A man who traveled to England
Here we go!
アキー、この本を書いた人に何か勉強したことはありますか?
はい、ブレンドン
インターネットでたくさんの情報を見つけた
何の情報?
この金蔵は誰だったの?
彼はエドの時代の最後に
日本に生まれたサムライだった
19世紀の中に
そうなの?
そうです。彼は英語を勉強するためにイギリスに行ったのです。
当時、日本人は海外に旅行することは知らなかったのです。
まあ、詳細は知りませんが、彼は日本を秘密に帰ってきたのです。
素晴らしいです。
わかりましたか?
質問をもう一度行ってみましょう。
誰が書いたのですか?
A. ブレンドン
B. アイドル
a samurai who taught english or c a man who traveled to england 答えは c a man who traveled to england
質問はその手紙を書いたのは誰 a ブレンダン b 英語を教えた武士
c イングランドに渡った男性 答えは c イングランドに渡った男性となります
Good work. OK, now let's move on to Tuesday's dialog.
Here's the question.
Which of the following is true?
A. Roxy got lots of sleep on the flight.
B. Grandpa will buy some fresh fruit.
C. Grandma is at home.
Listen up.
Grandpa!
Roxy, I'm so happy you're here. Welcome back.
Where's Grandma?
She needed to freshen up a bit. She'll be back shortly.
How was your flight?
It was fine. I slept a lot on the plane.
My, how you've grown, Roxy. You're a lovely lady now.
Thank you, Grandpa. I'm excited to start my new year in university.
Let's get you home first
Are you hungry?
Starving
Oh, here comes your grandmother now
Grandma
How did you do?
Alright, let's check out the question one more time
Which of the following is true?
A. Roxy got lots of sleep on the flight
B. Grandpa will buy some fresh fruit
C. Grandma is at home
答えはA. ロキシーは飛行中にたくさん睡眠をとった
B. おじいさんは新鮮な果物をちょっと買う
C. おばあさんが家にいる
答えはA. ロキシーは飛行中にたくさん睡眠をとったとなります
Alright, next up, it's Wednesday's dialogue.
What does the S in S.K. Jennings stand for?
A. Stanford
B. Samuel
or C. Summer
Listen carefully.
It's my pleasure to welcome to the show, best-selling author S.K. Jennings.
Thank you, Kelly.
Should I call you Mr. Jennings?
Please, call me Sam.
Ah, that's what the S stands for, right?
Yes, Samuel. And the K stands for Kentworth.
Interesting.
Sam, your fantasy novels have sold millions of copies worldwide.
It still surprises me.
Did you always know you would grow up to be a famous writer?
ケリー I never imagined it in my wildest dreams
I just liked reading books
Were you able to catch that?
Let's go over the question one more time
What does the S in S.K. Jennings stand for?
A. Stanford
B. Samuel
Or C. Summer
答えは?
B. Samuel
質問は?
S.K.ジェニングスのSは何の略?
A.スタンフォード
B.サミュエル
C.サマー
答えはB.サミュエルとなります
Alright and last up is Thursday's dialogue
Let's check out the question
Which of the following did Yoshi not ask Barbara?
A. Whether she finished her workout or not
b. Whether the car is hers or not
c. What she does for a living
Here we go!
Hi, Barbara!
Oh, hi, Yoshi! Sorry, I didn't see you.
Did you finish your workout already?
Yes, I had an early start today.
Is this your car?
That's right.
Wow, you must be rich to drive such a nice car.
Well, I do work hard at my job.
Okay, I won't ask you what you do for a living.
I know it's rude to ask such questions.
I appreciate that.
Anyway, have a nice workout. Bye!
All right, did you do okay?
Let's check out the question one more time.
答えは
質問は次のうちヨシがバーバラに聞かなかったことは
A. 彼女が運動を終えたかどうか
B. 彼女が運動を終えたかどうか
その車が彼女のものかどうか
See 彼女が何の仕事をしているか
答えはSee 彼女が何の仕事をしているかとなります
さあリスニングチャレンジ 出来はいかがでしたでしょうか
出来があんまり良くなくても気にしないでくださいね
お続けになっていればどんどん正答率は上がっていきますよ
今週練習した表現を使って会話の実践練習をしましょう ok here's the first シチュエーション
イマージェンデス
元彼から電話があり今の彼は良くないから別れるように言われます 反論してください例えば私が誰と付き合うべきか言うなんて
そんなことが言える立場なのあなたが私を振ったのよ 私は彼をとても愛しているし
彼も私を愛してくれています
二度と電話してこないで
など
それではヒントを差し上げておきましょう
誰々と別れる
これはbreak up withというフレーズを使いましょう
もう一度シチュエーションを確認します
元彼から電話があり
今の彼は良くないから別れるように言われます
反論してください
例えば
私が誰と付き合うべきか言うなんて
そんなことが言える立場なのあなたが私を振ったのよ 私は彼をとても愛しているし彼も私を愛してくれています
二度と電話してこないでなど さあ元彼からこう言われますよ
あなたならどう言いますか
それではここでローザさんの答えを聞きましょう
では内容を順番に確認しましょう
Who are you to は何々するなんて何様のつもりなのかでしたね
Break up with はヒントでお出ししたように誰々と別れる
I love him so much and he loves me too. Don't ever call me again.
Don't ever は何々するな Don't よりも強い禁止を表しています
それではローザさんの答えをもう一度聞きましょう
あなたは遠距離恋愛中の彼女と
翌日彼女の地元にあるヒロトランドに行く予定です
終電に乗って彼女のところに行くことになっていましたが
乗り遅れてしまいました電話をかけて説明してください 例えば
や仕事の後駅に走ったんだけど終電がすでに出たことがわかっただけだったんだ 大丈夫始発に乗って10時にゲートで会うことにするよ
など さあヒントを差し上げておきましょう
仕事の後これはアフターワークが使えます 最終電車これは the last train を使いください
さあもう一度シチュエーションを確認します
あなたは遠距離恋愛中の彼女と
翌日彼女の地元にあるヒロトランドに行く予定です
終電に乗って彼女のところに行くことになっていましたが
乗り遅れてしまいました
電話をかけて説明してください
例えば
やあ仕事の後駅に走ったんだけど
終電がすでに出たことがわかっただけだったんだ
大丈夫
始発に乗って10時にゲートで会うことにするよ
など
さあ彼女にこう聞かれますよ
あなたならどう言いますか
それではここでデイビッドさんの答えを聞きましょう
では内容を順番に確認しましょう
Only two
は落胆を表す何々しただけだった
Findに後続する説の過去完了形は
過去の時点までに起こった内容を表す形
駅に着いた時には
すでに電車が行ってしまっていたことを表しています
Don't worry, I will take the first train and meet you at the gate at 10
At the gate at 10は文集職
文末に置かれます
それでは、デイビッドさんの答えをもう一度聞きましょう。
ああ、うん。
actually last year i missed the last train from nikko to tokyo because i got on the local train going in the opposite direction
there was no hotels or anything in the area but thankfully my friend came and picked me up by car and took me in time to get the last shinkansen
oh a friend in need is a friend indeed right
というわけで今日はこの辺で
bye